

### **Contact**

Address
Ballia , India 277001

Phone
9450473559

avinashsingh4494@gmail.com

Portfolio

www.growskillit.com/MyProfile

in LinkedIn

www.linkedin.com/in/

avinash-singh-452072116

**GitHub**github.com/Avinash4494

#### **Technical Profile**

HTML

CSS

MySQL

Adobe Photoshop

Bootstrap

WordPress

Figma

Microsoft Access

**SASS** 

**Responsive Design** 

Wireframe

Prototype

## **Competencies**

User Interface Design

Web application development

**MS Office** 

Figma

Creative overall experience of 4 years facilitating and supporting human interactions with complex systems and software. UI Developer with 2 years of experience creating streamlined and responsive designs through programming and design. Talented at planning and creating websites and UI interfaces using technologies HTML, Bootstrap, Figma and CSS etc. Consistently employed understanding of user psychology throughout design process.

## **Work History**

### UI/UX Developer | Wipro Technologies

Bangalore - August 2022 - Current

- Improved and expanded project platforms using HTML/CSS to develop rich User Interfaces.
- Communicated with product managers and UX designers to translate project requirements and business objectives into polished user interfaces.
- Worked with design teams, project managers and business analysts to create intuitive and easy-to-use software.
- Designed UIs within frontend web frameworks, exploiting associated templates and tools to shorten development times.
- Technologies Used: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Figma, MySQL

## **Technical Support | Wipro Technologies**

Chennai - June 2019 - June 2022

- Installed, modified, and repaired software and hardware to resolve technical issues.
- Provided Tier 1 IT support to non-technical internal users through desk side support services.
- Responded to support requests from end-users and patiently walked individuals through basic troubleshooting tasks.
- Explained technical information in clear terms to non-technical individuals to promote better understanding.
- Provided on-call support for critical issues related to [Software].
- Documented support interactions for future reference.
- Monitored systems in operation and quickly troubleshot errors.
- Assisted with updating technical support best practices for use by team.

### **Education History**

**Vel Tech Technical University** 

Chennai | Jun 2015 - Apr 2019

# Certifications

2023-01| Figma

# **Client Projects**

# AARADHYA CARGO MOVERS

Aaradhya Cargo and Movers Bangalore is one of the most reputed logistics companies in India with several branches all over India.

### **UTPANN**

Utpann Seeds and Beyonds is a key stakeholder in fueling Green Revolution that begins with the seed, the most decisive input in agriculture.

### **GROWSKILL IT**

We have eminent training partners from Industry, who already are the working professionals with a wide range of references and Experiences.